export const quiz = {
    topic: 'Carbon footprint',
    totalQuestions: 10,
    perQuestionScore: 1,
    questions: [
        {
            question: 'What is the most common source of household energy in rural India?',
            choices: ['Solar power', 'Biogas', 'Firewood', 'Electricity'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Firewood',
            explanation: 'Firewood is the most common source of  household energy in rural India due to its availability and low cost.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Which Indian city has been recognized for its efforts in waste segregation and recycling?',
            choices: ['Mumbai', 'Delhi', 'Ahemdabad', 'Indore'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Indore',
            explanation: "Indore has been recognized for its outstanding efforts in waste management, including segregation and recycling.",
        },
        {
            question: 'How can using a pressure cooker help reduce carbon emissions in Indian households?',
            choices: ['It uses more water', 'It increases cooking time', 'It releases more heat', 'It cooks food faster, saving energy'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'It releases more heat',
            explanation: 'Pressure cookers cook food faster, saving energy and reducing cooking time, which leads to lower carbon emissions.',
        },
        {
            question: 'What is a common sustainable practice for water conservation in Indian agriculture?',
            choices: ['Unregulated water usage', 'Overhead sprinkler systems', 'Drip irrigation', 'Flood irrigation'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Drip irrigation',
            explanation: 'Drip irrigation delivers water directly to the plant roots, minimizing water wastage and promoting efficient water use.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Which mode of transportation is most energy-efficient for daily commuting in Indian cities?',
            choices: ['Motorbike', 'Bicycle', 'Auto-rickshaw', 'Private car'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Bicycle',
            explanation: 'Bicycles are the most energy-efficient mode of transportation as they do not rely on fuel and produce no emissions.',
        },
        {
            question: 'What is a simple way to reduce electricity consumption in Indian homes?',
            choices: ['Using incandescent bulbs', 'Keeping appliances on standby', 'Using LED bulbs', 'Leaving lights on all night'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Using LED bulbs',
            explanation: 'LED bulbs use significantly less electricity and have a longer lifespan compared to incandescent bulbs, reducing overall energy consumption.',
        },
        {
            question: 'What is the environmental benefit of using public transportation like buses and trains?',
            choices: ['It reduces the number of vehicles on the road', 'It increases air pollution', 'It leads to more traffic congestion', 'It consumes more fuel per person'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'It reduces the number of vehicles on the road',
            explanation: 'Public transportation reduces the number of private vehicles on the road, thereby decreasing traffic congestion and lowering overall emissions.',
        },
        {
            question: 'Which Indian state is known for its extensive use of wind energy?',
            choices: ['West Bengal', 'Bihar', 'Rajasthan', 'Tamil Nadu'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Tamil Nadu',
            explanation: 'Tamil Nadu has made significant investments in wind energy and has one of the largest wind power capacities in India.',
        },
        {
            question: 'How does planting trees in urban areas help reduce carbon footprint?',
            choices: ['Trees consume more water', 'Trees produce carbon dioxide', 'Trees absorb carbon dioxide and release oxygen', 'Trees increase the temperature'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Trees absorb carbon dioxide and release oxygen',
            explanation: 'Trees absorb carbon dioxide and release oxygen, which helps in reducing the overall carbon footprint and improving air quality.',
        },
        {
            question: 'What is a common practice in Indian households to save water?',
            choices: ['Keeping the tap running while brushing teeth', 'Using a bucket for bathing instead of a shower', 'Washing cars with a hose', 'Watering plants during midday'],
            type: 'MCQs',
            correctAnswer: 'Using a bucket for bathing instead of a shower',
            explanation: 'Using a bucket for bathing instead of a shower can significantly reduce water usage, helping in water conservation.',
        },
    ],
}